And now it's six. We're looking at the seasonal displays that are popping up everywhere
these days. How will they decorations? They've come a long way since they started. 13 news
now, anchor Phillip Townsend, looked at the history behind Christmas ornaments.
Whatever you celebrate in December, it probably has some tradition behind it. One of the most
well-known traditions during Christmas decorating the tree, of course. How do that start? And why
Why do we do it?
Well, the modern Christmas tree is believed to have started
in 16th century Germany.
Small evergreen trees were decorated with things like
candles, apples and berries.
They were called paradise trees and church plays.
The trees eventually made their ways
into the homes of devout Christians,
a tradition that's spread across Europe.
The first time they showed up in America,
likely around 18th or 19th century.
As time went on, ornaments became more artful.
started seeing tinsel and silk and hand-blown glass bulbs.
It then launched into this big commercial industry of its own, shedding most of its
religious significance by the mid-20th century.
And today there's an ornament pretty much for anything you can think of.
For 13 News Now, I'm Philip Taylor.